<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Thought Experiment on Rishikesh Sreehari</title>
    <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/categories/thought-experiment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thought Experiment on Rishikesh Sreehari</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 21:03:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/categories/thought-experiment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Man from the Future: A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/man-from-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 21:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/man-from-the-future/</guid>
      <description>The Experiment The Man from the Future is a thought experiment that I’ve been exploring over the years to understand the basics of everything we’re experiencing today ranging from food to our gadgets. Human history is quite fascinating and the pleasures we’re enjoying today has been achieved through multiple iterations of science, technology or culture, built upon the knowledge of past generations. The first principle’s thinkingand Thomas Thwaites’s Toaster Projecthad a great influence on this thought experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ovarian Lottery: A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/ovarian-lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/ovarian-lottery/</guid>
      <description>The Thought Experiment Warren Buffet explains the concept with a thought experiment when a Genie appears 24 hours before you were born. The genie gives you the wish that you determine the economic and social system into which you are going to emerge. There is a catch though as you do not have any control over where you would be born. If you play the lottery, you do not know whether you’re going to be:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
