<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Rishikesh Sreehari</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Rishikesh Sreehari</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 21:28:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curator Economy: Why Human Curation matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/curator-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 17:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/curator-economy/</guid>
      <description>Anamaria Luga in Beyond on Curator Economy
The Boom of Creator Economy With the rising popularity of social media and the internet, the creator economy is at an all-time high. In 2021 alone, the creator economy has seen a record funding of $1.3 billion. The cost of creating content continues to go down as more content creators are appearing online. The shift of content creation from big corporations to independent small creators around the globe has resulted in an age where we are overloaded with the vast availability of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delta-4 Theory: How to Evaluate your Startup Idea?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/delta-4-theory-how-to-evaluate-your-startup-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/delta-4-theory-how-to-evaluate-your-startup-idea/</guid>
      <description>Efficiency Scoring of an Idea Since human beings are hacking evolution, all inefficient things are in the past and efficient things are in the future. Wealth is generated when businesses help humans from point A to point B in a more efficient manner. This theory can be used to test an idea or an existing business. The efficiency score of a business solution or approach can be represented on a scale of 1-10 by the amount of efficiency it creates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ovarian Lottery: A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ovarian-lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ovarian-lottery/</guid>
      <description>The Thought Experiment Warren Buffet explains the concept with a thought experiment when a Genie appears 24 hours before you were born. The genie gives you the wish that you determine the economic and social system into which you are going to emerge. There is a catch though as you do not have any control over where you would be born. If you play the lottery, you do not know whether you’re going to be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 2 Training: The Art of Slowing Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zone-2-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 21:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zone-2-training/</guid>
      <description>In a nutshell, zone 2 training involves training at a low-intensity level for a longer period of time. The goal of zone 2 training is to sustain an intensity for longer periods of time such that heart rate lies in the range of 60-70% of the maximum heart rate value. Training at this intensity is incredibly easy and boring at the same time. When I started zone 2 training, I was a bit sceptical as it seemed too easy and I always had the attitude of ‘go hard or go home’ when it comes to training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27 Lessons I’ve learnt in 27 Years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/27-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 22:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/27-lessons/</guid>
      <description>JOMO &amp;gt; FOMO. Embracing Joy of Missing Out (JOMO) over Fear of Missing Out (FOMO) is the key to happiness and fulfilment over a long time. Organic Farming might sound sustainable and fancy, but it is not practical to use it to feed the rising population. Also, it is quite unsustainable considering the amount of land it uses. Learning doesn’t end in school and is a lifelong process. Self-learning is key in the 21st century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IKEA Effect: Why DIY Products make us happier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ikea-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 18:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ikea-effect/</guid>
      <description>Source: Sketchplanations
When instant cake mixes were introduced in the 1950s to simplify life, American housewife was reluctant to buy them. It made cooking easy. Manufacturers had to change the recipe to add an egg to improve sales. Subway is popular because it gives people the feeling that they are making their own sandwich and it allows for customization. People are ready to pay a premium for apple plucking even though the actual cost of apples are less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliance Bias: Brilliance as a Male Trait</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/brilliance-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 20:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/brilliance-bias/</guid>
      <description>Source: Sketchplanations
Our history books include few women, so subconsciously since we are young, men are our first thought when we consider brilliant people. Because of this underrepresentation, STEM careers that often need brilliance have fewer women employed. Many studies have indicated that women often suffer from impostor syndrome, which prevents them from pursuing STEM careers since brilliance is often seen as a male characteristic. A 2018 study surprisingly found that people were 40% less likely to refer a woman for a job that required high levels of brilliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonance Journal as a Tool for Self-Discovery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/resonance-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 11:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/resonance-journal/</guid>
      <description>Ali Abdaal
How does it work? How an entry looks in Resonance Journal
The concept is simple. Every time you come across a video, podcast, job, article, book, project, etc that resonates with you, add it as an entry to the resonance journal. Use the existing tags or create one if it doesn’t exist. Over time you would see a pattern or a common thread of things that resonates with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learnt from my  first 100 Email Subscribers on Substack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/first-100-email-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 11:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/first-100-email-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>Just Start! I created the first logo using some random font from the internet!
I have always struggled to start. Being a person who cares a lot about design and aesthetics, I usually spend a crazy amount of time tweaking things to launch the perfect product. When I started 10+1 Things, I decided that I’m gonna start anyway irrespective of the design or clarity. If you check the initial few issues in the archive, you can see that the style was different and not uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I keep a Stress Journal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/stress-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 21:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/stress-journal/</guid>
      <description>Source:Mintexports
The idea of a stress journal is simple. Any time you face anxiety or stress, write the date and write about the feeling and what triggered it. I usually give it a score out of five to indicate how much it bothers me. Every time I open the journal to write a new entry, I go through all the previous entries. I cross out entries that don’t bother me anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Lessons I Learned from the 30 Day Meditation Challenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons-30-day-meditation-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 19:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lessons-30-day-meditation-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Amir Motlagh
I had struggled with a bit of anxiety and restlessness ever since I quit my job last year. I had received suggestions from many people to try meditation, but I was over-sceptical considering the scent of spirituality it had. But then I happened to read a Twitter thread by Naval Ravikant. Navalis someone who I admire a lot and his ideas and philosophies resonate a lot with me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
