<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Concept on Rishikesh Sreehari</title>
    <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/categories/concept/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concept on Rishikesh Sreehari</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 18:53:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/categories/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The IKEA Effect: Why DIY Products make us happier</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/ikea-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 18:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/ikea-effect/</guid>
      <description>Source: Sketchplanations When instant cake mixes were introduced in the 1950s to simplify life, American housewife was reluctant to buy them. It made cooking easy. Manufacturers had to change the recipe to add an egg to improve sales. Subway is popular because it gives people the feeling that they are making their own sandwich and it allows for customization. People are ready to pay a premium for apple plucking even though the actual cost of apples are less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliance Bias: Brilliance as a Male Trait</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/brilliance-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 20:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/brilliance-bias/</guid>
      <description>Source: SketchplanationsOur history books include few women, so subconsciously since we are young, men are our first thought when we consider brilliant people. Because of this underrepresentation, STEM careers that often need brilliance have fewer women employed. Many studies have indicated that women often suffer from impostor syndrome, which prevents them from pursuing STEM careers since brilliance is often seen as a male characteristic. A 2018 studysurprisingly found that people were 40% less likely to refer a woman for a job that required high levels of brilliance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
