<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Rishikesh Sreehari</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rishikesh Sreehari</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Man from the Future: A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/man-from-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 21:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/man-from-the-future/</guid>
      <description>The Experiment The Man from the Future is a thought experiment that I’ve been exploring over the years to understand the basics of everything we’re experiencing today ranging from food to our gadgets. Human history is quite fascinating and the pleasures we’re enjoying today has been achieved through multiple iterations of science, technology or culture, built upon the knowledge of past generations. The first principle’s thinking and Thomas Thwaites’s Toaster Project had a great influence on this thought experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curator Economy: Why Human Curation matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/curator-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 17:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/curator-economy/</guid>
      <description>Anamaria Luga in Beyond on Curator Economy
The Boom of Creator Economy With the rising popularity of social media and the internet, the creator economy is at an all-time high. In 2021 alone, the creator economy has seen a record funding of $1.3 billion. The cost of creating content continues to go down as more content creators are appearing online. The shift of content creation from big corporations to independent small creators around the globe has resulted in an age where we are overloaded with the vast availability of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delta-4 Theory: How to Evaluate your Startup Idea?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/delta-4-theory-how-to-evaluate-your-startup-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/delta-4-theory-how-to-evaluate-your-startup-idea/</guid>
      <description>Efficiency Scoring of an Idea Since human beings are hacking evolution, all inefficient things are in the past and efficient things are in the future. Wealth is generated when businesses help humans from point A to point B in a more efficient manner. This theory can be used to test an idea or an existing business. The efficiency score of a business solution or approach can be represented on a scale of 1-10 by the amount of efficiency it creates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Curate my Newsletter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-i-curate-my-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-i-curate-my-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>The Structure Before I start explaining my process, it is important to discuss the structure of my newsletter. I’ve structured my newsletter in such a way that it explores some key areas/topics that I’m exploring in my life and during the week. Every edition of my newsletter follows this structure (it has evolved a bit over time) as described below:
✍️An article on my blog: The first link is generally a blog post on this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boring Phone: How to Stop Phone Addiction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/boring-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 23:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/boring-phone/</guid>
      <description>The idea was to ensure that I consume as less information as possible via my smartphone and reduce as many triggers that force me to pick up my phone. My primary means of information consumption was through my laptop and I used my phone to consume content only while travelling or during unavoidable circumstances. Following are some steps, and tips that I followed in the Boring Phone framework such that I’m less addicted to my smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ovarian Lottery: A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ovarian-lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ovarian-lottery/</guid>
      <description>The Thought Experiment Warren Buffet explains the concept with a thought experiment when a Genie appears 24 hours before you were born. The genie gives you the wish that you determine the economic and social system into which you are going to emerge. There is a catch though as you do not have any control over where you would be born. If you play the lottery, you do not know whether you’re going to be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Versioning Manifesto</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog-version-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog-version-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Maintaining a clear and organized record of changes to your blog is essential for both your readers and yourself. This manifesto outlines the principles and practices for effective versioning and changelog management tailored specifically for a personal blog.
Guiding Principles Changelogs are for humans, not machines: Entries should be written in a way that is clear, concise, and easy to understand. Every version is documented: Ensure there is an entry for each version of your blog, no matter how small the change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Single Purpose Devices in a Distracted World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/single-purpose-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 20:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/single-purpose-devices/</guid>
      <description>Importance of Single Purpose Devices To start with, a single-purpose device is a device that serves only one purpose or function. On the contrary, the smartphone is a multipurpose device that serves many functions. The problem with multipurpose devices like a smartphone is a distraction. Imagine you’re trying to read on your smartphone and suddenly you’re distracted by notification and the flow is lost. Even though there are many multipurpose devices in our lives, nothing has penetrated into our lives like a smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>72-Hour Rule: How to Stop Impulse Buying?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/72-hour-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 22:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/72-hour-rule/</guid>
      <description>The Triggers Let’s not blame marketers, it is their job to promote products and force us to buy. Over the years marketers have mastered various techniques that force consumers to impulse purchase products. Some techniques have evolved over time as in recent times there was a drastic shift in shopping patterns with the rising popularity of e-commerce sites. But underlying psychology remains the same and today every app that has something to sell is fighting for our attention, forcing us to buy stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Calendar: How to take Control of Your Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/energy-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 23:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/energy-calendar/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/SahilBloom/status/1542867629047746561?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;quot;&amp;gt;July 1, 2022&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;The Method The framework or method is simple. Simply, colour code the events in your calendar at the end of the activity or day using the following or something similar:
🌲Energizer: Energized me and made me think about it for hours 🔵Energy Gainer: Created some energy. ⭐️Neutral: Not too great or too bad 🔺Energy Drainer: Sucked the energy out of me A screenshot of last Friday’s calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 2 Training: The Art of Slowing Down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/zone-2-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 21:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/zone-2-training/</guid>
      <description>In a nutshell, zone 2 training involves training at a low-intensity level for a longer period of time. The goal of zone 2 training is to sustain an intensity for longer periods of time such that heart rate lies in the range of 60-70% of the maximum heart rate value. Training at this intensity is incredibly easy and boring at the same time. When I started zone 2 training, I was a bit sceptical as it seemed too easy and I always had the attitude of ‘go hard or go home’ when it comes to training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022: A Year of Hope</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 12:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022-planning/</guid>
      <description>Goals To be fit and healthy by end of 2022. Create alternate work streams and a passive income by the end of 2022. Master programming and transition my career into a more data oriented one. Objectives To achieve the goals mentioned in the previous section, the following objectives have been laid out. Some of these objectives are interconnected and contribute to more than one of the goals.
🏋Weight At the time of writing this post, my weight is 70 kgs, putting me in the slightly obese range on the BMI scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27 Lessons I’ve learnt in 27 Years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/27-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 22:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/27-lessons/</guid>
      <description>JOMO &amp;gt; FOMO. Embracing Joy of Missing Out (JOMO) over Fear of Missing Out (FOMO) is the key to happiness and fulfilment over a long time. Organic Farming might sound sustainable and fancy, but it is not practical to use it to feed the rising population. Also, it is quite unsustainable considering the amount of land it uses. Learning doesn’t end in school and is a lifelong process. Self-learning is key in the 21st century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IKEA Effect: Why DIY Products make us happier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ikea-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 18:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ikea-effect/</guid>
      <description>Source: Sketchplanations
When instant cake mixes were introduced in the 1950s to simplify life, American housewife was reluctant to buy them. It made cooking easy. Manufacturers had to change the recipe to add an egg to improve sales. Subway is popular because it gives people the feeling that they are making their own sandwich and it allows for customization. People are ready to pay a premium for apple plucking even though the actual cost of apples are less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliance Bias: Brilliance as a Male Trait</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/brilliance-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 20:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/brilliance-bias/</guid>
      <description>Source: Sketchplanations
Our history books include few women, so subconsciously since we are young, men are our first thought when we consider brilliant people. Because of this underrepresentation, STEM careers that often need brilliance have fewer women employed. Many studies have indicated that women often suffer from impostor syndrome, which prevents them from pursuing STEM careers since brilliance is often seen as a male characteristic. A 2018 study surprisingly found that people were 40% less likely to refer a woman for a job that required high levels of brilliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Start an Attention Diet?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/attention-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 19:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/attention-diet/</guid>
      <description>Mark Manson
What is an Attention Diet? An Attention Diet is to be followed in the 21st century, an era where we are bombarded with information. Attention diet focuses on the amount of media, content and socializing people are doing these days, eventually distracting themselves. The goal of an attention diet is to find highly nutritious sources of information and relationships to build our lives around them. The diet gives more importance to quality over quantity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonance Journal as a Tool for Self-Discovery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/resonance-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 11:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/resonance-journal/</guid>
      <description>Ali Abdaal
How does it work? How an entry looks in Resonance Journal
The concept is simple. Every time you come across a video, podcast, job, article, book, project, etc that resonates with you, add it as an entry to the resonance journal. Use the existing tags or create one if it doesn’t exist. Over time you would see a pattern or a common thread of things that resonates with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learnt from my  first 100 Email Subscribers on Substack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/first-100-email-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 11:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/first-100-email-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>Just Start! I created the first logo using some random font from the internet!
I have always struggled to start. Being a person who cares a lot about design and aesthetics, I usually spend a crazy amount of time tweaking things to launch the perfect product. When I started 10+1 Things, I decided that I’m gonna start anyway irrespective of the design or clarity. If you check the initial few issues in the archive, you can see that the style was different and not uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I keep a Stress Journal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/stress-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 21:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/stress-journal/</guid>
      <description>Source:Mintexports
The idea of a stress journal is simple. Any time you face anxiety or stress, write the date and write about the feeling and what triggered it. I usually give it a score out of five to indicate how much it bothers me. Every time I open the journal to write a new entry, I go through all the previous entries. I cross out entries that don’t bother me anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Rules: An Eater’s Manual: Book Summary &amp; Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/food-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 21:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/food-rules/</guid>
      <description>Michael Pollen
This book is a must-read if you are looking to get some insights on diet and leading a healthy diet.
How the book has changed me? As mentioned earlier many ideas were already known to me. But the book brought more clarity to my notion against processed food. The French Paradox mentioned in the book was also thought-provoking. The practice of having a colourful diet backed up with the idea of phytochemicals was new to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Lessons I Learned from the 30 Day Meditation Challenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lessons-30-day-meditation-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 19:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lessons-30-day-meditation-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Amir Motlagh
I had struggled with a bit of anxiety and restlessness ever since I quit my job last year. I had received suggestions from many people to try meditation, but I was over-sceptical considering the scent of spirituality it had. But then I happened to read a Twitter thread by Naval Ravikant. Navalis someone who I admire a lot and his ideas and philosophies resonate a lot with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I built my Digital Garden using Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/build-a-digital-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 21:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/build-a-digital-garden/</guid>
      <description>Read more about the History and Ethos of Digital gardens.
Features Publication Dates are not important to Digital Gardeners. Posts are connected via references or common themes. There are no featured posts or chronological list of items. Readers can enter through any note, follow any trail and exit as they wish. Digital Gardens are constantly evolving over time and are never complete. There is no pressure to publish a perfect post in digital gardens as notes grow over time just like plants in a garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almanack of Naval Ravikant: Book Summary &amp; Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 13:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/</guid>
      <description>How the book changed me? The life philosophy of Naval resonates with me a lot and this book strengthened it. The ideas and his vision towards his life had a huge impact on me and this book would be one the best books I’ve read. His view on judgement and leverage have been very influential to me. This is one book that I revisit a lot many times a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readwise Review: How to remember what you read?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/readwise-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 18:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/readwise-review/</guid>
      <description>My Current Reading Flow Readwise has many features which personally helped me a lot to remember what I’ve read. Readwise is now an integral part of my personal knowledge management flow. To give a quick idea, this is the reading workflow which I use to remember what I’ve read:
Mark highlights and take notes while reading on my Kindle. Export highlights and notes from Readwise to Obsidian(The software I use for personal knowledge management).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show Your Work by Austin Kleon: Book Summary &amp; Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/show-your-work-by-austin-kleon-book-summary-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 12:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/show-your-work-by-austin-kleon-book-summary-notes/</guid>
      <description>How the book changed me? The book completely changed me and my thought process of sharing stuff online. I’m now more comfortable putting my thoughts online and having more confidence in talking about my work in public. As said earlier, I started this blog inspired by this book and became a keen follower of Austin’s blog. In fact the newsletter I run on this blog, ‘10+1 Things‘ was also inspired by his newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons Why I Decided to Start a Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/5-reasons-why-i-decided-to-start-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/5-reasons-why-i-decided-to-start-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have always loved reading but somewhere in the past few years, I had lost the habit of reading. I decided to take up 52 books in 52 weeks challenge in 2021 and was in constant search of finding books to read. That’s when I stumbled upon the book, ‘‘Show your Work!’ by Austin Kleon, shared by the productivity Youtuber Ali Abdaal whom I have been following for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Changelog/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/colophon/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Stack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/futurestack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/futurestack/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/library/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/timeline/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Stack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lifestack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lifestack/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Name</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/name/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Then</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/then/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/then/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on UAE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/travel/UAE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/travel/UAE/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/travel/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Doing Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/now/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Doing Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/now-2024-06-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/now-2024-06-09/</guid>
      <description>single</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
