<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Rishikesh Sreehari</title>
    <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Rishikesh Sreehari</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 20:39:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Curate my Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/how-i-curate-my-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/how-i-curate-my-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>The Structure Before I start explaining my process, it is important to discuss the structure of my newsletter. I’ve structured my newsletter in such a way that it explores some key areas/topics that I’m exploring in my life and during the week. Every edition of my newsletter follows this structure (it has evolved a bit over time) as described below:
✍️An article on my blog: The first link is generally a blog post on this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boring Phone: How to Stop Phone Addiction</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/boring-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 23:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/boring-phone/</guid>
      <description>The idea was to ensure that I consume as less information as possible via my smartphone and reduce as many triggers that force me to pick up my phone. My primary means of information consumption was through my laptop and I used my phone to consume content only while travelling or during unavoidable circumstances. Following are some steps, and tips that I followed in the Boring Phone framework such that I’m less addicted to my smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Single Purpose Devices in a Distracted World</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/single-purpose-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 20:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/single-purpose-devices/</guid>
      <description>Importance of Single Purpose Devices To start with, a single-purpose device is a device that serves only one purpose or function. On the contrary, the smartphone is a multipurpose device that serves many functions. The problem with multipurpose devices like a smartphone is a distraction. Imagine you’re trying to read on your smartphone and suddenly you’re distracted by notification and the flow is lost. Even though there are many multipurpose devices in our lives, nothing has penetrated into our lives like a smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>72-Hour Rule: How to Stop Impulse Buying?</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/72-hour-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 22:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/72-hour-rule/</guid>
      <description>The Triggers Let’s not blame marketers, it is their job to promote products and force us to buy. Over the years marketers have mastered various techniques that force consumers to impulse purchase products. Some techniques have evolved over time as in recent times there was a drastic shift in shopping patterns with the rising popularity of e-commerce sites. But underlying psychology remains the same and today every app that has something to sell is fighting for our attention, forcing us to buy stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Calendar: How to take Control of Your Time</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/energy-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 23:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/energy-calendar/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/SahilBloom/status/1542867629047746561?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;quot;&amp;gt;July 1, 2022&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;The Method The framework or method is simple. Simply, colour code the events in your calendar at the end of the activity or day using the following or something similar:
🌲Energizer: Energized me and made me think about it for hours 🔵Energy Gainer: Created some energy. ⭐️Neutral: Not too great or too bad 🔺Energy Drainer: Sucked the energy out of me A screenshot of last Friday’s calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Start an Attention Diet?</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/attention-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 19:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/attention-diet/</guid>
      <description>Mark Manson
What is an Attention Diet? An Attention Diet is to be followed in the 21st century, an era where we are bombarded with information. Attention diet focuses on the amount of media, content and socializing people are doing these days, eventually distracting themselves. The goal of an attention diet is to find highly nutritious sources of information and relationships to build our lives around them. The diet gives more importance to quality over quantity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonance Journal as a Tool for Self-Discovery</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/resonance-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 11:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/resonance-journal/</guid>
      <description>Ali Abdaal
How does it work? How an entry looks in Resonance Journal
The concept is simple. Every time you come across a video, podcast, job, article, book, project, etc that resonates with you, add it as an entry to the resonance journal. Use the existing tags or create one if it doesn’t exist. Over time you would see a pattern or a common thread of things that resonates with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I keep a Stress Journal</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/stress-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 21:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/stress-journal/</guid>
      <description>Source:Mintexports
The idea of a stress journal is simple. Any time you face anxiety or stress, write the date and write about the feeling and what triggered it. I usually give it a score out of five to indicate how much it bothers me. Every time I open the journal to write a new entry, I go through all the previous entries. I cross out entries that don’t bother me anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I built my Digital Garden using Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/build-a-digital-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 21:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/build-a-digital-garden/</guid>
      <description>Read more about the History and Ethos of Digital gardens.
Features Publication Dates are not important to Digital Gardeners. Posts are connected via references or common themes. There are no featured posts or chronological list of items. Readers can enter through any note, follow any trail and exit as they wish. Digital Gardens are constantly evolving over time and are never complete. There is no pressure to publish a perfect post in digital gardens as notes grow over time just like plants in a garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readwise Review: How to remember what you read?</title>
      <link>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/readwise-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 18:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jade-sable-e0c36b.netlify.app/readwise-review/</guid>
      <description>My Current Reading Flow Readwise has many features which personally helped me a lot to remember what I’ve read. Readwise is now an integral part of my personal knowledge management flow. To give a quick idea, this is the reading workflow which I use to remember what I’ve read:
Mark highlights and take notes while reading on my Kindle. Export highlights and notes from Readwise to Obsidian(The software I use for personal knowledge management).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
